for Adam Hill, Las Vegas Review Journal.
Um, you you said to Paul you you weren't
sure even till tonight. So, did they not
tell you along the way in the process
like you're the guy to to be ready and
you really had to wait till today? And I
guess um you know where in the process
did you feel like this would be a good
fit for you?
>> Well, whatever team was going to select
me and be a good fit, but deep down my
heart, I knew the Raiders are most
likely going to be the best fit because
of the coaching staff. I think it really
fits my play style great because all the
great teammates on offense and defense.
They're stacked because of the great
ownership. Whether it's Mr. Davis, Mr.
Brady. I mean, what a better situation
to walk into. So, I think all the stars
are aligning here and I'm just very
blessed to be in this position.
>> Hey, Fernando. Uh, congratulations. You
mentioned Mr. Brady. I've seen you over
the years talk about how much you looked
up to him throughout ever since he
started playing football. What does it
mean for him to be part of the group
that uh drafted you and what have your
interactions been with him like so far?
>> It means a ton and I think it's a huge
edge for the football club to be able to
have such a a source of knowledge,
intelligence, and experience all in one,
especially as an owner. It's something
very rare that you get. So, I'm looking
forward to diving in, getting all the
resource I can from him and learning
from him, the great coaches, and the
other great players we have on the team.
Hello, Fernando. This is Hondo
Carpenter. When you look back at your
career through high school to Cal to IU
to the Raiders, it's really been a
journey of faith, both your personal
faith, but also betting on yourself. You
could have gotten more money or gone
other places, but you chose IU because
of the coaching. I'm just curious, how
much is faith in you and not not just
your spiritual faith, but your faith in
and trust in you and what you do and
your team part of who you are as a man?
>> Well, first off, I'm a man of God and I
believe that God has a plan. He's
blessed my family, blessed me, and I
just can't thank him enough. And second
of all, I also think that f that fortune
favors the bold and that sometimes when
you're bold and you bet on yourself,
it'll work out most of the times. And if
it doesn't work out, at least you'll be
able to at least sleep easy at night 20
years down the road knowing you did
everything possible to accomplish your
goals. And that's what I look forward to
doing, doing everything possible to
accomplishing my goals with this
football club and helping any way I can.
Fernando, how you doing? Q Myers, Raider
Nation Radio 920. Uh, we know that the
journey is just now beginning in the
NFL. What is it that you're most excited
about the opportunity that you bring to
this team and just what you want to
learn and what you're going to bring
when you get boots on the ground?
>> Well, I'm really excited to meet
everyone at the Silver and Black
organization, Raider Nation, and just
really excited to learn what a great
ownership group we have, what a great
coaching staff, and what a great
players. I mean, this roster is stacked
with talent and intelligence. I'm
looking forward to diving in, being one
of the guys, and helping the team any
way possible to win.
>> Go ahead, Levi Edwards.
>> Hey, Fernando. Jesse Merrick here from
Silver and Black Sports Network.
Congratulations, man. Uh you said you
felt like it was a perfect fit with this
staff. We've heard that you've been
working on installing this offense. I'm
just curious with what you know about
Kubak scheme. Why is it you feel you fit
perfectly into this offense?
>> Well, I've watched a lot of film. I
wasn't necessarily installing this
offense. those installing general NFL
offense, getting more accustomed to
under center play and general west coast
concepts which does fit under this tree
which now paid off like and taking that
risk talking about fortune favors the
bold rolling the dice on that a little
bit but this scheme it really allows a
quarterback to be a point guard. I
believe that my job, we have so many
great playmakers, whether it's from the
outside, tight end, running back, or
offensive line, I just get the ball to
the playmakers and do my part of the
offense and be be my 111th. And at that
point, I believe this offense allows a
quarterback to do that. And with such
great coaches, I look forward to
immersing myself into it.
>> Sorry about Sorry about that. Uh Levi
was with Raiders.com. Congratulations.
Obviously, when you heard your name
called, you know, what were the
emotions? What were the feelings that
came with that? And what were just some
of the people that came to your mind as
that moment came and rushed to you?
>> Well, it was great. I didn't know to
celebrate when I got the phone call or
heard on the TV. So, that was a little
bit of a a mixup there, but when I first
got the call, the emotions,
it was before the draft, I was about to
just burst out with emotion. I told
myself, "Hey, hold it in, hold it in. It
have it hasn't even happened yet." So,
and then once it happened, I was I was
ecstatic
and I heard my mom like, "I was so proud
of you." And so, that that that that
kind of broke me there. And I'm just so
happy to have such a great support
system and so grateful for and blessed
for the opportunity.
>> Hey, Fernando, I'm just wondering what
excites you the most about the city of
Las Vegas and getting your boots on the
ground here as you become a Raider.
my top for 30 visit. I had a fantastic
time. I believe that well from an
outside perspective, especially me being
and growing up in Miami, Las Vegas, it
had a little bit of a like a different,
you know, vibe than I thought. But when
I touched down at Las Vegas and I saw
what the city was all about my first
time being there, I was like, "Wow, this
is amazing." And this is everything has
lived up to be and even better than
that. So, I look forward to the city. It
looks like everyone's really friendly.
There's a lot of great cities outside of
the strip and the strip itself. Uh the
strip talks for itself.
>> Hi Fernando. Mark Anderson at the AP. Um
you've always been sort of the underdog
um through your college career having to
prove yourself. How does that help you
now being the one being the number one
pick overall uh as far as guess keeping
that mentality?
>> Well, I believe I'm still the underdog
as although the draft was today once I
got drafted, I'm now a part of the NFL
and I can tell you right now, I am not
one out of 32. Although I was picked
today, one out of 32. I'm not one out of
32 quarterbacks at this moment. So, I
need to work every single day possible
because I'm on the bottom of the totem
pole. whatever you know everyone wants
to rank me. I I don't know those
specifics but I'm with the bottom of the
totem pole right now and I gotta first
earn the respect to my teammates
earn earn that equity and I also just I
got to immerse and I'm just you know
ready to do whatever the team needs to
help uh whatever the team needs and
calls me to do to help them win.
Fernando uh Chris Matthews here in Las
Vegas. Can you hear me?
>> Hear you loud and clear.
>> Oh, good. Okay. With the CBS affiliate
here, just real quick question. Kind of
a two-part question. Uh the the underdog
from high school who might not have
continued football and and I I read
somewhere you were like the 288th
recruit in the state of Florida. Then
you go on to be the number one pick in
the NFL draft. I guess that message to
young kids that to never give up, to
follow your dreams, um to continue to to
pursue whatever you dream of becoming.
And then kind of the second part is that
your work ethic I guess is unmatched
maybe next to Max Crosby. Talk about
that.
>> Well, I need to prove my work ethic and
I've heard Max Crosby has the best work
ethic and it's second to none and so I
look forward to learning from him and a
lot of other leaders and players on the
team.
However, that underdog mentality is
always still there. But it's having
unwavering optimism. And the message
that my mom gave me that helped unlock
the exponential growth is don't put a
ceiling over your head. Although they
they ranked me 288th or the stat you
just said in Florida. I didn't see
myself as that because I didn't see
myself as a ranking. I just saw me as me
and try to work on myself every single
day as I look forward once I get hey
coach Kubak, coach Janoko and coach
Sullivan say hey you got to work on and
whatever you know Max Gby whatever he
says hey you got to work on this I'm all
for it so be awesome
>> Fernando congratulations
um I just want to you know the Raiders
are one of the most historic franchises
in the NFL what does it mean to be
wearing the shield
right now. And what was it like putting
that hat on your head?
>> It means everything. The legacy that the
Raiders has here. I mean, it's it it's a
cornerstone franchise of the NFL. And
just researching all the history. I got
to meet Jim Plunkett at the Heisman
ceremony. Another Latino QB. Was awesome
to connect with him. Look forward to
connecting with more of the history. I
wore number 15 in college. So, if I get
the opportunity to wear number 15 in the
Raiders, that would be fantastic. But I
don't know if I've earned that yet
because of the legendary Tom Flores, who
also played quarterback and evidently
was just a Raiders icon. So, I have a
lot of uh earning and proving to do, but
I look forward to diving more in the
Raiders history, you know, whether it's
having the commitments to excellence,
you know, whether it's honoring the
silver and black and Raider Nation. I'm
excited to dive head first into it.
>> Awesome. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Hey, Fernando. Hey, Fernando. Uh Sam
Warren with Athletic. Um
congratulations. Uh you mentioned the
players that are going to be surrounding
you with the Raiders. Um they spent a
ton in in free agency um this past
March. Um what's it like, you know,
being the number one pick, but going
into a situation where the team has
already invested so much to be around
you and kind of help you uh start your
NFL career?
>> I don't think it's just investing in me.
I think it's investing in the entire
team, everybody on the team, whether
it's the offensive line position,
quarterback position, defense, it just
shows a commitment to excellence that
the Raiders have and so I'm I'm a stack
to be a part of it and to play a small
part into it.
>> Hey, Fernando Pagutz here again from the
Raiders. Um, how how important was it
for you to stay home to celebrate this
with your family? And also, is there
really a math going on in your backyard
right now?
Oh, excuse me. Can you say that again?
>> Paul Guett is here from the Raiders. Uh,
again, so I heard the heard the
question. The Matanza going on.
>> The Matanza, you guys cooking a pig in
the backyard. Is that
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It meant a
lot. Although, to be quite honest,
although I love Pittsburgh and would
love to be there. I want to be a great
rep of the NFL. I mean, but the Raiders
are number one for me and it's really
easy for my mom to go here to Las Vegas
tomorrow. And so, that was number one. I
wanted there. I I to be honest, I chose
the Raiders over Pittsburgh or whatever
team I was going. I mean, at this point,
I chose the Raiders over Pittsburgh
because I wanted my mom to be there.
It'd be hard for her to take two two
trips like that really back to back.
Yeah.
>> So, that that that was one of the main
reasons. And and then Yeah, they are
they are doing a pig in the backyard, so
everyone's eating it right now. So,
hopefully they'll leave some for me. But
if if not, I'll I'll still get something
in my system.
Hi Fernando, Brandy Flores, Raider
Nation Radio 920. Congratulations. You
made history becoming the first Cuban
American quarterback to be drafted first
overall. Your family being a Latino is
super important to you. I don't know if
you know this, but Raider Nation has a
lot of Latino fans. How excited are you
to connect with them and to continue to,
you know, put your culture forward as
you make your ways in the NFL?
Culture is everything and I believe that
it makes the person who they are and how
they were raised and
Latinos like to do it big and that's
what we did at the party. A lot of
family, a lot of hugs. So, and I know
the Raiders have if not the most I mean
they definitely have the most Hispanic
following. So, or or if they don't have
the most, it's definitely in the top two
or three. So, I I look forward to
immersing myself in that community,
giving back any way I can. and and yeah,
>> thank you.
>> Hey, Fernando Sean Zatell, Vegas Sports
Today. What would you say is the best
attribute that you're bringing to the
Raiders?
>> I would say the best attribute I'm
bringing to the Raiders is resilience.
Still need to earn every single day and
prove that I can play at this level at
high level. But the resilience whether
it's you know bad practice and be able
to take that bump and falling down using
that bump as an accelerator to then
learn from it improve and so every step
along the way I pride myself on
exponential growth every single year.
I've done it through all my college
years. So look forward to keeping that
trend up and that trend is is met by
hard work, discipline and unwavering
optimism.
>> Congratulations Fernando. Uh we're
excited to have you in Las Vegas. Uh
seeing you hug your mom was so special
and your guys' relationship is awesome
to see. Can you take me back to a memory
you have and a conversation you had when
you thought this dream would be possible
with your
>> Yeah, the dream of playing in the NFL we
thought was going to be possible
especially at the end of the college
football playoff. And at that point we
were we were ecstatic. However, we
wanted to focus on the task at hand.
Then after the college football playoff,
we're at their home in Miami and kind of
realized, especially this week, like,
wow, like I'm about to play on an NFL
team. So to have that opportunity, it's
it's great. And it's very surreal. Very
surreal. Hasn't sunk in yet. And I don't
know if it'll if it'll sink in in the
next couple of days, but whenever it'll
sink in, they'll not change. I'm ready
to get to work.
>> Okay, last one's going to be Myra.
Thank you.
Hello.
>> How you doing?
>> Oh,
Raiders.
Mrs. Gomez,
I mean
I I I'm sorry. I I love the I love the
rib. I love the rib and that and that
that's my favorite part. But there's a
big debate whether the rib or the
cheekbone. But all all with that, I
mean, I just can't thank my family
enough. I'm really just excited to be
immersed in the Raiders and Spanish
community, whether it's, you know,
hopefully doing interviews in Spanish or
or if it's just being a part and giving
back and just being the best player I
can do, become the best serve the team
and best serve my teammates and just
best serve the organization. I'm ready
to rock and roll with it and look
forward to talking to you and thank you
again.
>> All right, that's it. Thank you so much,
Fernando. Really appreciate it. Thanks
everybody.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks. Bye.